Correct, you've mastered it.
答对了 你掌握得很清楚嘛
That's it for today's class.
那今天的课就上到这里
No way. I didn't understand a thing.
不会吧 我完全不懂
What are you doing?
你干嘛啦
You didn't understand?
你没听懂吗
You did? Let me see!
难道你就有听懂吗 借来看看
Wait, no!
不行啦
Hey, Sajo.
喂 佐城
Do you want to see mine?
你要看看我的吗
Thanks, but no.
不用了
Little Sajo, are you sure?
小佐城 你没问题吗
It's none of your business.
要你管
That question was really hard.
刚才那题好难哦
Yes, I'm a bit worried about the next exam.
是啊 我开始担心下次的考试了
Where are you going?
你要去哪里
Cafeteria.
吃东西
(A Buffet to Celebrate the End of the First Semester!)
(记念第一学期结束的帕菲！)
It's too hot outside today. I hope I can find a seat inside.
现在外面有够热的 要是里面有位子就好了
Found him, Sajo!
啊 这不是佐城学弟吗
Well, you're looking for me for something, right?
请问你们找我有事吗
Otherwise, I don't think we're familiar enough to have meals together.
不然我们应该还没熟到会一起吃饭吧
Eh? Is that so?
咦 是吗
Why is Yuyu so fond of you? Did you use some kind of pay-to-win item?
为什么由结这么欣赏你 你是用了什么课金道具吗
Sajo, you're so cunning.
佐城你太狡猾了
You don't even know what that is, senior.
学姐 你根本不知道她说的是什么东西吧
If I could buy such a thing in reality, I would have bought it long ago.
现实中要是买得到那种东西 我早就买了好吗
Oh, that's what it is?
原来...是那类的东西啊
Rin told me you were sick. Are you feeling better now?
我听凛学姐说你感冒了 你现在康复了吗
Yes, I'm fine now.
对 已经好了
That's good to hear.
那真是太好了
About the question you asked earlier.
关于你刚才的疑问
There's a reason why Yuyu called for you.
由结特地找你过来是有原因的
I'm not going to beat around the bush.
我就不拐弯抹角了
Do you want to join the student council?
你要不要加入 风纪委员会？
I'm not talented in that regard.
小生并非此等人才
The student council president is retiring this fall.
风纪委员长今年秋天就要卸任了
But we didn't manage to recruit any boys from the first or second year.
但完全没有一二年级的男生加入
The girls seem to be just here for fun.
女生则是让人感觉是玩票性质
Their intentions are too obvious.
她们的意图太明显了
They are clearly using the student council as a status symbol.
摆明就是把风纪委员会 当成是一种地位象征
In fact, the only male member we have is Ichinose.
实际上 目前也只有一之濑同学一个男生
No, umm… I…
这个嘛...小生...敝人...
And then we thought of you.
所以我们就想起了你
Just like when you advised me, we hope you can lead the council.
就像当时你给我建言一样 我希望你能支援委员会
But the structure will only change in the second semester, won't it?
可是委员会的体制 要在第二学期才会改变吧
That's why I hope you start considering this now.
所以我希望你现在就开始考虑
Has anyone ever asked anything of me?
以前有人如此有求于我吗
No, never!
不 没有
But…
但是…
Please, Sajo!
佐城学弟 拜托你了
Sajo… you…
佐城...你这小子
Hey… you…
我说你啊...
I'm sorry.
对不起
No, this is a misunderstanding!
啊 不是...
Considering this situation,
有...有鉴于此
I really don't think I'm capable of being on the student council.
我认为我实在无法胜任风纪委员一职
Please allow me to refuse…
请容我拒绝...
Your hair…
你的头发...
What… what's wrong?
我...怎样？
Why is it messy on one side only?
为什么你的头发只有一边乱糟糟的
Ouch!
好痛啊...
I can feel your chest!
碰到胸部了啦...
Gosh, stand still.
真是的 你乖乖站好
Done!
好了
Um, Natsukawa…?
那个 夏川...
What is it?
怎么了...
Would 5000 yen be enough?
我付你五千块够吗
I… I don't want it.
我才不要咧
Drowning and nighttime accidents are common in August.
八月容易发生溺水事件和夜间事故
Cyberbullying on social media is also increasing.
网络社群媒体的受害事件也日渐增加
I hope you remember that you are a member of this school and abide by the rules during the holiday…
希望大家暑假期间也谨记学生身份 好好遵守校规...
He is that male student council member.
他就是那个男风纪委员
A bear-like guy who's popular among the girls.
很容易跟女生打成一片的熊系男孩
I'm Shinomiya, the student council president.
我是四之宫风纪委员长
She is very popular.
学姐超受欢迎耶
No wonder everyone wants to join the council.
难怪大家都想加入委员会
I'm sure you all know by now.
想必各位同学也都知道
The first week of August will be the campus open day event.
八月的第一周将举办校园参观日活动
Even though some of you are not involved in this event,
即使有些人与本次活动无关
I hope you remember the character of a Koetsu High School student.
但仍希望各位谨记 身为鸿越高中在校生的品格
Character?
品格吗...
Next is the student union.
接下来换学生会了
Looks like my elder sister fits the role.
老姐这样看起来也是有模有样的
What kind of magic is this?
这是什么魔法啊
I sincerely hope all of you
我衷心祝福各位同学
have a fulfilling and meaningful summer holiday.
能够度过一个充实又有意义的暑假
Senior Yuki is still so handsome, and his voice is still so deep.
结城学长还是又帅 声音又有磁性
No wonder the girls are amazed.
也难怪女生们都赞叹不已
Please be quiet, everyone.
同学们安静
There's one last thing we need to decide.
最后有件事必须定案
About the campus open day during the summer holiday.
暑假期间的校园参观日
Anyone volunteers to help out?
有人自愿帮忙吗
If no one volunteers, I will do the picking.
没人举手的话 就让老师来决定咯
Okay, those who don't have club activities during the holiday, stand up!
好 暑假期间没有社团活动的人 请起立
Let's decide by rock-paper-scissors.
那就猜拳决定吧
Sajo, why don't you volunteer?
佐城 干脆就你来吧
Yamazaki, shut up.
山崎你闭嘴
Sajo, are you willing to help?
佐城同学 你愿意帮忙吗
Sorry, I just recovered from a serious illness.
抱歉 我大病初愈
You were fine long ago!
你明明早就好了
Okay, time for rock-paper-scissors!
好 那就来猜拳吧
We need one boy and one girl, so you guys need to split up.
男女各需一名 所以你们就男女分开猜拳哦
Tabata, when was the last time I talked to you?
田端 我有几个月没跟你说话了啊？
-Who knows? -Let's do this fair and square…
-谁知道 -我们就堂堂正正...
-Hurry up! -Sorry.
-快开始啦 -抱歉
Rock, paper, scissors.
石头剪子布
Well, good luck.
那就拜托你咯
But I have cram classes to attend.
可是我还要去补习班耶
You should have said it earlier.
输了才讲是想怎样
Okay, the winner is Ichinose.
好 一之濑同学赢了
And Natsukawa will join too.
那女生这边就是夏川同学了
S-Sorry.
不好意思
It's okay.
没关系
Natsukawa is going?
是夏川同学呀
You seem a bit happy about it.
瞧你开心的...
Tabata, I heard you have cram school?
田端 听说你补习很忙对吧
Do you want me to replace you?
我可以跟你换哦
Uh… yeah…
呃 嗯...
Ms. Otsuki, can I help?
大槻老师 我可以帮忙哦
Really?
真的吗
It would be great if you could come.
佐佐木同学愿意帮忙就再好不过了
But is it okay with your soccer club?
但你足球队那边没问题吗
The first-years don't need to compete, so it's okay.
一年级没有比赛 没问题的
What a guy!
太会耍帅了吧
-A stunning team. -So this means that Sasaki…
-俊男美女的组合 -也就是说佐佐木同学他...
Tabata, is it okay?
田端同学你也同意吗
Ah… yes…
啊 嗯...
Don't worry. I proposed it myself.
你不用有所顾虑 毕竟是我自愿的
Tabata, good luck in cram classes.
田端 补习加油啊
Um, okay…
好...
He's indeed handsome.
不愧是帅哥
Let's work together, Natsukawa!
夏川 请多指教咯
Looking forward to it, Sasaki.
请多指教 佐佐木同学
They seem like a great match.
他们两个感觉好相配哦
Um, yeah.
嗯 是啊
Little Sajo… how can you be so calm?
小佐城 你怎么可以这么淡定啊
Well… they are indeed a good team.
这个嘛...他们两个搭档很不错啊
You loser.
你这鲁蛇
So, the first semester ends here.
那第一学期就到此结束了
Don't forget the first day of school.
大家不要忘记返校节哦
Okay.
好
Gosh, give me a break.
真是的 饶了我吧
-What's wrong? -Nothing.
-怎么了 -没事
By the way,
话说
you almost got to be alone with Aika.
你差点就能靠猜拳跟小爱独处了耶
None of your business.
不用你多管闲事
You might experience withdrawal symptoms if you don't see Aika during the summer.
暑假见不到小爱 你会不会难熬到受不了啊
Maybe.
可能会哦
Club activities are quite tough.
社团活动还满辛苦的耶
I only get to rest on weekends and during the Ghost Festival.
基本上只有周末跟盂兰盆节才放假
You don't have to force yourself to hang out with me.
你不用勉强出来跟我玩啦
No, I want to play with you.
那怎么行 我想跟你出去玩
We can't miss the sea and fireworks!
绝对不能没有海边跟烟火
Oh you…
你啊...
Sorry to keep you waiting.
久等了
Great! A buffet to celebrate the end of the first semester!
好耶 记念第一学期结束的帕菲
Let's eat.
我开动咯
Can I invite others to join us?
机会难得 我可以叫其他人一起来吗
Sure, the more the merrier.
好啊 人多热闹
Really? Then… can I invite Sajo?
真的吗 那找小佐城如何？
Why… why are you mentioning him now?
你...干嘛突然提起他啊
You know.
你懂的
(Dreaming Boy is a Realist, The)
《满怀美梦的少年是现实主义者》
BINAN BOOKSTORE SECOND-HAND BOOKS
(滨南书店) (二手书交易)
Boss, I've sorted the books.
店长 我整理完书籍了
Really? That was fast.
真的吗 这么快啊
Hiring you was the right decision.
录取你还真是选对人了
One more person can make such a huge change.
多了一个人手竟然就有这么大的差别
Thank you for your good work.
当然也多亏了你精明能干
I've worked in a convenience store before.
因为我以前在便利商店打过工
This workload actually makes me feel idle.
这点工作量反而让我闲得发慌
BINAN BOOKSTORE SECOND-HAND BOOKS
(滨南书店) (二手书交易)
Don't joke with us!
你开什么玩笑啊
Give it back to me!
还给我！
You can't touch it, can you?
你拿不到吧
What do you want, shorty?
就凭你这个矮冬瓜
Say something.
你说话啊
Hey, stop it.
喂 你们快住手
Who are you? You want a beating?
你是哪冒出来的 欠揍吗
Okay, you can beat me if you want.
好啊 你们想揍就揍啊
Are you okay?
你没事吧
What… what are you doing?
你搞屁啊
Are you hurt? Can you stand up?
你没受伤吧 站得起来吗
Let's go. This guy must be an idiot.
我们走 这人有病吧
-Idiot.
白痴
What's your name?
你叫什么名字
Sa… Sasaki…
我叫笹木...
Sasaki Kota.
笹木光太
So it's Sasaki.
原来是笹木不是佐佐木
Kota, do you remember your home number?
光太小弟弟 你记得家里电话号码吗
BINAN BOOKSTORE
(滨南书店)
I see. You must have been really scared.
这样啊 你一定很害怕吧
But it's okay now.
不过已经没事咯
Ko!
小光
Sis!
姐姐
-Are you injured? -I'm fine.
-你有没有受伤？ -我没事
That's good.
那就好
And you are…
请问你是...
I was the one who called you.
我是刚刚打电话联络你的人
My name is Sajo Wataru.
我叫佐城涉
Kota was being harassed by a group of middle school students under the overpass over there.
你弟弟在那个高架桥下 被一群初中生缠住
Oh… thank you very much, Mr. Sajo.
真的非常感谢你 佐城先生
The aura of a big sister! So gentle!
大姐姐的气场 好轻柔啊
Is this… what a college girl is like?
这就是所谓的女大学生吗
I've never felt like this before!
这种感觉可真是新鲜
It's nothing.
哪里哪里
More importantly, you should check
话说回来 待会你最好检查一下
if there are strange traces in his backpack.
书包跟里面的东西 有没有不寻常的痕迹
Can't let them bully him all the time.
毕竟如果他经常被欺负的话就不好了
Okay! I got it.
好的 我明白了
Kota, you should be fine now, right?
光太小弟弟你有好一点了吗
Don't go to remote places alone next time.
下次要小心别再单独去人少的地方哦
Your sister will worry about you.
不然你姐姐会担心的
I'm sorry.
对不起
You don't need to apologize. Just be careful next time.
你不用道歉 下次小心就好了
It's great, Kota.
太好了 小光
A kind big brother helped you.
有好心的大哥哥救了你
Ah… it's nothing.
没...没什么啦
Big brother…
她叫我大哥哥...
Mister, as usual.
老板 老样子
Are you a regular at some coffee shop?
你以为你是咖啡厅的常客吗
Never mind.
当我没说
So this is the vice president of our student union.
我们学校的学生会副会长 竟然是这副模样
Shut up, idiot.
少啰嗦 你这笨蛋
Why are you getting up so early during summer holiday?
话说回来 暑假你还这么早起啊
Because the early bird makes money.
早起的鸟儿有钱赚嘛
You don't make money in school, but you do at work.
上学没钱可领 但打工可就不一样了
You work in a second-hand bookstore, right? Is it that easy?
你是在二手书店打工吧 有那么轻松吗
This is the good thing about a private shop.
个人经营的店铺就是有这好处
Unlike those chain stores, the work won't keep increasing.
跟事情永远做不完的连锁店不一样
I just need to finish what needs to be done.
只要把分内工作做完就好 轻松多了
So the student union is like a chain store.
原来学生会就是连锁店啊
That's not the same.
不一样吧
Is the preparation for the campus open day going smoothly?
校园参观日的准备工作还顺利吗
You work together with other departments, but the student union is still in charge, right?
虽说是跟风纪委员共同举办 但负责指挥的是学生会吧
Don't underestimate your big sister. I didn't become the vice president with nothing.
别小看你老姐 我这副会长可不是白当的
Apologies for any offense.
那真是失敬了
By the way, were you invited to join the student council?
话说 有人邀请你加入风纪委员吗
How did you know…
你怎么知...
Shinomiya told you?
四之宫学姐跟你说的吧
Something like that.
算是吧
What's your relationship with her?
比起这个 你们两个是什么关系啊
Relationship… Like siblings, I guess.
能有什么关系... 就像姐弟般的关系吧
I don't care though.
什么关系我是都无所谓啦
Are you going to join?
你要加入风纪委员会吗
I've known for a long time that they want more male members.
我是知道她们一直想多找些男生
Of course not.
我当然不可能加入
The burden would be too heavy.
怎么想都觉得负担太重了
Then you can join us.
那你加入学生会吧
What are you doing?
你干嘛啊
Why?
为什么啊
I don't want to give my position to some loser I don't know.
毕竟我不想让位给来路不明的废柴
Clauma…
克劳玛蒂...
I grant you the right
我决定特别赏赐你一个权利
to cheer for the top student, Shinonome Claudine Marika.
让你替东云‧克劳蒂娜‧茉莉花 也就是全年级第一的我本人加油
Luring Natsukawa to your side will only make you look worse.
拉拢夏川反而会让你相形失色哦
H-How rude!
你很失礼耶
-Any objections? -No, but I'm also a loser of the Sajo family.
-怎样？ -但我也算是佐城家的废柴啊
Aren't you very good at organizing documents?
你很擅长文书处理啊
Is that considered a strength?
那也算是长处吗
Anyway, I'm quite serious about it. Think about it.
总之学生会的事 我是颇认真的你好好考虑一下
Are you really serious? You must be kidding me.
你真的是认真的吗... 是在开玩笑吧
BINAN BOOKSTORE SECOND-HAND BOOKS
(滨南书店) (二手书交易)
A masterpiece to read before you die…
死前必读的杰作...
Isn't that a bit exaggerated?
有点太夸张了
No, it won't attract attention if we don't write it like this.
但是不这么写就无法引人注意了
Excuse me?
请问有人在吗
I'm coming.
我马上过去...
Hello, Mr. Sajo.
佐城先生 你好
H-Hello, long time no see.
你好...好久不见
Thank you for your help last time.
上次真是谢谢你了
We were in a hurry
当时我们匆匆忙忙地离开
and didn't realize you worked in a second-hand bookstore.
都没发现这里是二手书店
I didn't know there was such a store near my home.
原来我家附近还有这么一间店
Do you live nearby?
你住在这附近吗
Yes! I'm happy to get acquainted with a bookstore clerk.
是的 很高兴能认识书店店员
I should be the happy one.
该觉得开心的是我才对
Miss Sasaki seems very mature. I can't help but feel nervous.
笹木小姐你给人感觉很成熟 害我会不自觉紧张起来
Mature? Not at all.
哪有成熟
It's the first time someone said that to me.
这还是第一次有人这么对我说
People always say I'm childish.
之前我还一直被人家说幼稚
No, it's hard to imagine…
不 实在很难想象...
Uh, it feels a bit like sexual harassment.
呃 怎么有点像在性骚扰
Are you going to the campus today?
你今天是要回大学上课吗
No…
不是
But my school isn't really a campus.
不过我的学校并不太像大学啦
Is that so?
是吗
Yes, it's only for girls, so it's not very open.
嗯 因为只有女生 所以不怎么开放的感觉
What about you, Mr. Sajo?
那你呢？
Do you know Koetsu High School?
你知道鸿越高中吗
So you're a student there.
原来你是那里的学生啊
Koetsu High School is great!
鸿越高中很不错耶
The uniform is also very cute. It gives me a university feel.
制服很可爱 也很有大学校园的感觉
It's indeed pointlessly large.
校园的确是不知道在大什么的
Yes! The school is very spacious. How nice.
嗯 校园宽敞 我觉得真是一所好学校
So you're a student at Koetsu. No wonder you're so outstanding!
原来你是鸿越的学生 难怪这么优秀
Not at all.
不敢当
In my view, Miss Sasaki is the mature and flawless one.
在我看来 笹木小姐才是既成熟又清纯
Well… Mr. Sajo, you're exaggerating.
哪有...你太过奖了啦
What's with this vibe?
这股清纯感是怎么回事
It's too dazzling. I'm about to be devoured.
她散发出的光芒都要把我淹没了
You saved Kota last time…
之前我们家小光...
I want to thank you again.
我想再次感谢你救了我弟弟
I did as you suggested and checked the backpack.
我照你说的检查了他的书包
There was no damage, so I was relieved.
并没有发现什么损伤的痕迹 我就放心了
That's good.
那就好
How is Kota doing now?
后来光太小弟弟还好吗
Does he still feel scared?
他还会觉得害怕吗
I think you must have given him a lot of courage.
我想应该是你给了他很大的勇气
He's out playing today.
他今天也在外面玩耍呢
That's really great.
那真是太好了
Actually… there's something embarrassing.
其实...我有件羞于启齿的事
I haven't really talked to boys much,
就是我不太有机会跟男生说话
so now I'm benefiting a lot.
所以我真的受益匪浅
H-how should I put it…
这...该怎么说呢
Your parents must love you very much.
你爸妈一定很爱护你吧
That's right.
是这样没错...
I would say they probably over-protected me.
真要说的话 应该是他们有点保护过度了...
I talked too much, sorry.
我不小心聊太久了 真不好意思
This is a gift for saving my brother.
这是谢谢你救了我弟弟的谢礼
A small token of my gratitude.
小小心意 不成敬意
Thank you. It's not necessary though.
谢谢你 还让你费心了
No, I'm the one who should be thankful.
怎么会 该道谢的人是我
Can… can I come again?
我...还可以再来找你吗
O-Of course!
啊 当然没问题
BINAN BOOKSTORE SECOND-HAND BOOKS
(滨南书店) (二手书交易)
Looking at the size, it should be a handkerchief.
看这大小 应该是手帕吧
Is it a high-end one with lace?
是带有蕾丝的高档货吗
No, it must be a large handkerchief for men.
不对 一定是男用的大条手帕...
Huh?
咦
Do I…
我是不是...
give off a childish impression?
让人觉得很幼稚啊？